hey guys I want to tell you about a
brand new study that my team got
published
just yesterday colors that hit a print
in the Journal of applied biomechanics
and the title of the study was or is a
comparison of gluteus maximus biceps
femoris vastus lateralis EMG amplitude
in the barbell American and big hip
thrust variations so we looked at 13
trade women all bikini competitors or
power lifters and we have them performed
three different hip thrusts variations
we looked at mean and peak values in the
upper boots lower glutes hamstrings and
quads so let me show you the different
variations the standard hip thrust is
just like this we do three reps
to perform the American hip thrust you
could up lighter but this and it just
has a different feel to it
so the American if there's looks like
this and then the band hip thrust is
like this okay so let me talk about the
result basically the barbell hip thrust
seems to be the superior exercise for
the glutes it beat out the band of the
American hip restorations in most most
things most muscle activation
however the American hip thrust one
interesting other thing about the
American interest is that it activated a
little bit more hamstrings and a little
bit less quads than the barbell hip
thrust so if you're the type that feels
barbell refers in the quads a ton you
might like the american hip thrust more
but an interesting thing is that each
variation of each variation had certain
people who have their highest total with
that variation so for example sometimes
you'll get people who say I feel banned
hip thrust a lot more than barbell hip
thrust or I feel barbell hip thrust a
lot more than Danny address or I feel
American you dress way more than I feel
but on the press maybe they feel more in
the glutes and this study kind of shed
some light on that some people are
getting more
or glute activation depending on the
variation so when is determining what
exercise you're going to perform which
variation you're going to perform you
should take into account you know
comfort
some people feel a lot more comfortable
performing the band in trust some people
don't have access to do bands so they
have to do barbell some people you know
it feels easier on their back when they
do the American hip dress so take these
things into consideration because the
muscle activation wasn't totally
different between the three different
variations but I'm going to have a full
write-up on my blog and also a link to
download the full paper in case you want
to look at the tables and in the grass
associate with a study so take a look at
the blog thanks